When the game is over, the fun begins.
Wreck-It Ralph is a family, animation, comedy film directed by Rich Moore.
Wreck-It Ralph is the 9-foot-tall, 643-pound villain of an arcade video game named Fix-It
Felix Jr., in which the game's titular hero fixes buildings that Ralph destroys.
Wanting to prove he can be a good guy and not just a villain, Ralph escapes his game and lands in Hero's
Duty, a first-person shooter where he helps the game's hero battle against alien invaders.
He later enters Sugar Rush, a kart racing game set on tracks
made of candies, cookies and other sweets.
There, Ralph meets Vanellope von Schweetz who has learned that her game is faced with a dire threat
that could affect the entire arcade, and one that Ralph may have inadvertently started.
Wreck-It Ralph (voice), played by John C. Reilly.
Vanellope von Schweetz (voice), played by Sarah Silverman.
Fix-It Felix Jr. (voice), played by Jack McBrayer.
Sergeant Tamora Jean Calhoun (voice), played by Jane Lynch.
King Candy / Turbo (voice), played by Alan Tudyk.
Sour Bill / Zangief (voice), played by Rich Moore.
Wreck-It Ralph is a 2012 American animated comedy film
produced by Walt Disney Animation Studios.
It was directed by Rich Moore and produced by Clark Spencer, from
a screenplay by Phil Johnston and Jennifer Lee.
John Lasseter served as the film's executive producer.
Featuring the voices of John C.
Reilly, Sarah Silverman, Jack McBrayer, and Jane Lynch, the film tells the story of Ralph, an arcade
game villain who rebels against his "bad guy" role and dreams of becoming a hero.
The concept of Wreck-It Ralph originated in the late 1980s under the
working title High Score and evolved through various iterations.
Moore sought to capture an authentic video-game world by including real video game characters
like Bowser, Clyde, and Doctor Eggman, while focusing on creating new characters.
For animation, Disney introduced new reflectance
functions and a real-time virtual camera system.
The team researched candy factories and food photography to
inspire the design of the Sugar Rush game world.
Henry Jackman composed the score, and the soundtrack featured original
songs by Owl City, AKB48, and Skrillex, among others.
Wreck-It Ralph premiered at the El Capitan Theatre in Los Angeles on
October 29, 2012, and went into general release on November 2.
The film was a critical and commercial success, grossing $496 million worldwide against a $165 million budget and winning the Annie Award
for Best Animated Feature, as well as receiving nominations for the Golden Globe and Academy Award for Best Animated Feature.
A sequel, Ralph Breaks the Internet, was released in 2018.
The film explores themes of video game, support group, villain, bullying, medal.
The tone is lighthearted.